Every City Needs Its Heroes
The Interrupters is a documentary film directed by Steve James.
The Interrupters tells the moving and surprising stories of three Violence Interrupters — former gang
members who try to protect their Chicago communities from the violence they once caused.
Himself, played by Tio Hardiman.
Herself, played by Ameena Matthews.
Himself, played by Cobe Williams.
Himself, played by Gary Slutkin.
Herself, played by Caprysha Anderson.
Himself, played by Eddie Bocanegra.
The Interrupters is a 2011 documentary film, produced by Kartemquin Films, that tells the story of three violence
interrupters who try to protect their Chicago communities from the violence they once employed.
It examines a year in which Chicago drew national headlines
for violence and murder that plagued the city.
The film features the work of CeaseFire, an initiative of
the Chicago Project for Violence Prevention.
In 2004, Tio Hardiman (ex-Director of CeaseFire Illinois) created
and implemented The Violence Interrupter concept.
Violence interrupters Ameena Matthews, Cobe Williams and Eddie Bocanegra look back on their past
experiences with street violence to try to steer young men and women in the right direction.
Matthews, the daughter of former Chicago gang leader Jeff Fort, comes to the aid of the mother of Derrion Albert, a
Chicago high school student whose death made national headlines when it was captured on videotape.
Produced by Kartemquin Films, The Interrupters is directed by Steve James, director of the documentary
Hoop Dreams, and co-produced by Alex Kotlowitz, author of There Are No Children Here.
The film explores themes of hero, social work, redemption, gang leader, honor.
The tone is emotional.